JASHWANTH GOWDA R

Software Engineer - Flutter Developer

+919986621042 ■ webdeviash6@gmail.com

https://jashwanthgowda.vercel.app/

Bangalore,India



I'm a self-taught Software Engineer and Passionate Flutter Developer with 2+ years of experience, Primarily focused on Designing and Developing Flutter-based Applications. I have the experience of building Mobile Applications for Android using Flutter, Web Applications using Flutter, ReactJs, Opencart, WordPress, Ghost & Jekyll, and Responsive mobile-first sites with Bootstrap & Sass.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer -1,

Digital Green | July. 2021 - Nov. 2022

Developed and Implemented the below mobile and web application from the ground up:

- Farmstack Datahub FarmStack is a digital infrastructure for secured data sharing for food and agriculture.FarmStack helps users share data directly with each other and enforce usage policy that restricts unintended misuse of data. My role was to develop frontend side of this application using the React Library. Technologies used: Javascript, ReactJS, Mui, Bootstrap.
- KD Officer: A mobile app used by ground front line workers to collect farmer's crop harvest data that helps FPOs make informed decision about the sales planning. My role was to develop frontend side of this application using the Flutter Framework
- Explored new technologies and upgraded the existing tech stack.
- Responsible for all the Bug fixes, Documentation and feature implementation of the Flutter Consent Module
- Troubleshooted style issues, browser compatibility issues.

Software Engineer Intern

Vrook-Transforming Learning | Oct. 2019 - April. 2021

Designed, Developed and Implemented the below web application from the ground up:

- Booksbeka E-commerce Web Application Booksbeka.com is Karnataka's largest online store for engineering books,connecting students, colleges, and suppliers.My role was to design, develop and deploy this application using the OpenCart framework. Technologies used: Bootstrap, Sass, Javascript, Opencart, MySQL
- Open EDX Open edX is an open-source Edu-Tech Platform that provides learner-centric, enables online campuses, instructor-led courses, degree programs, and self-paced courses using a single platform. Key components of the project: Learning Management System (LMS) and Content management system(CMS).My role was to design and develop a Mobile Responsive Theme for Learning Management System (LMS). Technologies used: Bootstrap, Sass, Javascript, Docker and Kubernetes.
- Vrook-Content Web Application Designed and developed a web application to showcase the company's product and partnerships. Technologies used: WordPress, MySQL, Bootstrap, Sass and Elementor.
- Vrook-Blog Application Developed an end-to-end blogging platform that gives access to all teams in the company to share their experiences and knowledge. Technologies used: Ghost, MySQL, Bootstrap and Sass.

PROJECTS

Mishmi (Idu) Dictionary

Flutter, Dart

It is Android application, the primary focus of this beginner-friendly dictionary is aimed at younger generations of the Mishmi (Idu) community. This initiative is towards the promotion and preservation of Mishmi (Idu) language. Involved in designing and developing an audio player corresponding to word in the entire app and worked on some frontend features in this app.

Vernacular Archive of Northeast India - VANI

VANI for short - is an initiative aimed at documentation, digitization, and development of technology tools for the vernacular languages of Northeast India. Involved in designing and developing Mobile responsive theme customization for the website.

Foodveda E-commerce Web Application

This application was developed to help preserve traditional recipes and bring good health to consumers. Designed and developed this application using the OpenCart framework.Technologies used: Bootstrap, Sass, Javascript, Opencart, MySQL

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Telecommunication Engineering Don Bosco Institute Of Technology(VTU) July. 2015 - May. 2019

SKILLS

Technical Skills

Flutter

Dart Javascript

ReactJS

Riverpod

React-MUI

Bootstrap

Git

Firebase

Opencart

Wordpress

AWS (Amazon Web Services)

Apache

NGINX

Professional

Effective communication

Team player

LANGUAGES

Kannada (Native Proficiency)

English (Professional Working Proficiency)

INTERESTS

Coding

Cricket

Fitness

https://github.com/Jashwanth-Gowda-R in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jashwanthgowda-6666 yhttps://twitter.com/Jash_gowda_6